PETER BENVENUTO

SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER

EXPERIENCE

Senior Product Designer | 1Password

SEP 2024 - PRESENT, TORONTO, ON

- Owned 2 strategic growth initiatives for B2B products, driving growth for new product lines.
- Leading and mentoring 2 Junior or Intermediate Product Designers on a rotating schedule, focusing on growth strategy.
- Contributed to the Knox design system by developing 3 major core components and authoring documentation to support their usage.

Senior Product Designer | Capintel

MAR 2024 - SEP 2024, TORONTO, ON

- Developed strategic solutions for major U.S. clients, supporting successful expansion into the US market which saw 40% increase in sales volume.
- Established UX research processes and practices, leading the company's first user research studies and presenting insights through structured shareouts.

Senior Product Designer | Mozilla

MAY 2021 - FEB 2024, TORONTO, ON

- Owned design and strategy for our core global VPN product helping to increase MRR ~90% (\$334k to \$656k).
- Led design discovery and execution of all major features which grew our subscribers from 50k active subs to 127k active subs in 30 countries.
- Led initiative to improve the conversion funnel which, despite the fact that our customer base grew YoY, support tickets related to login dropped ~60% and account conversion improved ~50%.
- Led org-wide design system audit, rebuild and maintenance that was scaled to 4 products.

Product Designer | Intrado

MAR 2021 - MAY 2021, TORONTO, ON

 As the sole designer I was responsible for design strategy, research and execution of 5 major features of our core SaaS product.

Software Engineer | InvestCloud Inc.

SEP 2018 - MAR 2021, BURLINGTON, ON

 Design RESTful web APIs to seamlessly extract client data from existing CRM systems.

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, User Experience Design

SEP 2020 - DEC 2020, TORONTO, ON

York University | Bachelors, Political Science

SEP 2011 - 2014, TORONTO, ON

peterbenvenuto90@gmail.com 416-456-3019 linkedin.com/in/peter-benvenuto github.com/PeterBen90 peterbenvenuto.com

PROFILE

I'm a product designer and overall creative technologist with over 7 years of experience across disciplines. I started my career as a software engineer where I was building products for over 3 years, fast forward to now, where I enjoy driving strategy to help solve problems for users. I'm passionate about storytelling, crafting beautiful experiences, scaling design systems, and shoes.

DESIGN SKILLS

Growth strategy, Information architecture, Wireframing, UI prototyping, Interaction design, Motion design, Responsive design, Design systems, Visual design, User research and testing, Figma, Sketch, InVision, InVision Studio, Zeplin, Zeroheight, Adobe Creative Suite

DEV SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Redux, Material UI, Bootstrap, Bulma, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Java, Groovy, PostgreSQL, SQL, Git, Responsive design

CERTIFICATIONS

Become an AI Product Designer - Maven Software Engineering - Thinkful Enterprise Design Thinking - IBM Marketing - Humber College

MENTORING & TEACHING

Web Design Tutor @ CareerFoundry
FEB 2022 - PRESENT, REMOTE
UX Design Instructor @ BrainStation
NOV 2022 - PRESENT, TORONTO, ON